oddsmonkey.com 2019-08-31

# Privacy Statement - OddsMonkey

## How your personal information is used by DotNetPages Ltd group companies

 **Last updated March 2018.**

Your information will be held by DotNetPages Ltd, which trades as OddsMonkey, part of the DotNetPages Group.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is DotNetPages Ltd.

 **How we use your personal information**  
OddsMonkey is part of DotNetPages Ltd Group. This privacy notice is to let you know how companies within the Group promise to look after your personal information. This includes what you tell us about yourself, what we learn by having you as a customer, and the choices you give us about what marketing you want us to send you. This notice explains how we do this and tells you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

 **Our Privacy Promise**  
We promise:

  * To keep your data safe and private.
  * Not to sell your data.
  * To give you ways to manage and review your marketing choices at any time.

 **Data Protection law will change on 25 May 2018**  
This notice sets out most of your rights under the new laws.

* * *

### Who we are

DotNetPages Ltd is made up of many different legal entities. We’ll let you know which you have a relationship with, when you take out a product or service with us.   
If you have any questions, or want more details about how we use your personal information, you can ask us using our [secure online contact form](https://www.oddsmonkey.com/More/Support.aspx).

or write to us at  
DotNetPages GDPR Request, 15 Parsons Court, Aycliffe Business Park, County Durham, DL5 6ZE

* * *

### How the law protects you

As well as our Privacy Promise, your privacy is protected by law. This section explains how that works.

Data Protection law says that we are allowed to use personal information only if we have a proper reason to do so. This includes sharing it outside DotNetPages Group. The law says we must have one or more of these reasons:

  * To fulfill a contract we have with you, or
  * When it is our legal duty, or
  * When it is in our legitimate interest, or
  * When you consent to it.

A legitimate interest is when we have a business or commercial reason to use your information. But even then, it must not unfairly go against what is right and best for you. If we rely on our legitimate interest, we will tell you what that is.

Here is a list of all the ways that we may use your personal information, and which of the reasons we rely on to do so. This is also where we tell you what our legitimate interests are.

What we use your personal information for| Our reasons| Our legitimate interests  
---|---|---  
To manage our relationship with you or your business.  
To develop new ways to meet our customers’ needs and to grow our business.  
To develop and carry out marketing activities.  
To study how our customers use products and services from us and other organisations.  
To provide advice or guidance about our products and services.|  Your consent.  
Fulfilling contracts.  
Our legitimate interests.  
Our legal duty.|  Keeping our records up to date, working out which of our products and services may interest you and telling you about them.   
Developing products and services, and what we charge for them.  
Defining types of customers for new products or services.  
Seeking your consent when we need it to contact you.  
Being efficient about how we fulfill our legal duties.  
To develop and manage our brands, products and services.  
To test new products.  
To manage how we work with other companies that provide services to us and our customers.|  Fulfilling contracts.  
Our legitimate interests.  
Our legal duty.|  Developing products and services, and what we charge for them.  
Defining types of customers for new products or services.  
Being efficient about how we fulfill our legal and contractual duties.  
To deliver of our products and services.  
To make and manage customer payments.  
To manage fees and charges due on customer accounts.  
To collect and recover money that is owed to us.|  Fulfilling contracts.  
Our legitimate interests.  
Our legal duty.|  Being efficient about how we fulfill our legal and contractual duties.  
Complying with regulations that apply to us.  
To obey laws and regulations that apply to us.  
To respond to complaints and seek to resolve them.|  Fulfilling contracts.  
Our legitimate interests.  
Our legal duty.|  Complying with regulations that apply to us.   
Being efficient about how we fulfill our legal and contractual duties.  
To run our business in an efficient and proper way. This includes managing our financial position, business capability, planning, communications, corporate governance, and audit.| Our legitimate interests.  
Our legal duty.|  Complying with regulations that apply to us.   
Being efficient about how we fulfill our legal and contractual duties.  
To exercise our rights set out in agreements or contracts.|  Fulfilling contracts.|  Complying with regulations that apply to us.   
Being efficient about how we fulfill our legal and contractual duties.  
  
### Groups of Personal Information

We use many different kinds of personal information, and group them together like this.

Type of personal information| Description  
---|---  
Contact| Your name and email address as provided by you  
Transactional| Details about payments to and from your accounts with us.  
Contractual| Details about the products or services we provide to you.  
Locational| Data we get about where you are, such as may come from your mobile phone or the ip address where you connect a computer to the internet.  
Behavioural| Details about how you use our products and services.  
Technical| Details on the devices and technology you use.  
Usage Data| Other data about how you use our products and services.  
Consents| Any permissions, consents, or preferences that you give us. This includes things like how you want us to contact you or your preferences when using our products.  
  
### Where we collect personal information from

We may collect personal information about you (or your business) from other companies within the DontNetPages Group and from these sources:

Data you give to us:

  * When you apply for our products and services
  * When you use our internet services
  * In emails and communications
  * In customer surveys
  * If you take part in our competitions or promotions.

Data we collect when you use our services. This includes the amount, frequency, type, location, origin and recipients:

  * Payment and transaction data.
  * Profile and usage data. This includes the profile you create to identify yourself when you connect to our internet services. It also includes other data about how you use those services. We gather this data from devices you use to connect to those services, such as computers and mobile phones, using cookies and other internet tracking software.

Data from third parties we work with:

  * Companies that introduce you to us
  * Social networks
  * Agents working on our behalf
  * Market researchers

* * *

### Who we share your personal information with

We may share your personal information with companies within the DontNetPages Ltd Group and these organisations:

  * Agents who we use to help run your accounts and services and collect payments
  * Companies we have a joint venture or agreement to co-operate with
  * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site.
  * Organisations that introduce you to us

We may also share your personal information if the make-up of DotNetPages Ltd Group changes in the future:

  * We may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business, or our assets. Or we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them.
  * During any such process, we may share your data with other parties. We’ll only do this if they agree to keep your data safe and private.
  * If the change to our Group happens, then other parties may use your data in the same way as set out in this notice.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

* * *

### How we use your information to make automated decisions

We sometimes use systems to make automated decisions based on personal information we have about you or your business. These automated decisions can affect the products, services or features we may offer you now or in the future, or the price that we charge you for them.

Here are the types of automated decision we make:

 **Pricing**  
We may decide what to charge for some products and services based on what we know.

 **Tailoring products and services**  
We may place you in groups with similar customers. These are called customer segments. We use these to study and learn about our customers’ needs, and to make decisions based on what we learn. This helps us to design products and services for different customer segments, and to manage our relationships with them.

 **Detecting fraud**  
We use your personal information to help decide if your personal or business accounts may be being used for fraud or money-laundering. We may detect that an account is being used in ways that fraudsters work. Or we may notice that an account is being used in a way that is unusual for you or your business. If we think there is a risk of fraud, we may stop activity on the accounts or refuse access to them.

 **Opening accounts**  
When you open an account with us, we check that you or your business meets the conditions needed to open the account. This may include checking contact details and previous account records we hold for you.

 **Your rights  
** As a person you have rights over automated decisions.

  * You can ask that we do not make our decision based on the automation alone.
  * You can object to an automated decision, and ask that a person reviews it.

If you want to know more about these rights, please contact us.

* * *

### Sending data outside of the EEA

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

We will only send your data outside of the European Economic Area (‘EEA’) to:

  * Follow your instructions.
  * Comply with a legal duty.
  * Work with our agents and advisers who we use to help run your accounts and services.

If we do transfer information to our agents or advisers outside of the EEA, we will make sure that it is protected in the same way as if it was being used in the EEA. We’ll use one of these safeguards:

  * Transfer it to a non-EEA country with privacy laws that give the same protection as the EEA. Learn more [on the European Commission Justice website](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/adequacy/index_en.htm).
  * Put in place a contract with the recipient that means they must protect it to the same standards as the EEA. Read more about this here [on the European Commission Justice website](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/adequacy/index_en.htm),
  * Transfer it to organisations that are part of Privacy Shield. This is a framework that sets privacy standards for data sent between the US and EU countries. It makes sure those standards are similar to what is used within the EEA. You can find out more [about data protection on the European Commission Justice website](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/data-collection/data-transfer/index_en.htm).

* * *

### If you choose not to give personal information

We may need to collect personal information by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you.

If you choose not to give us this personal information, it may delay or prevent us from meeting our obligations. It may also mean that we cannot perform services needed to run your account or comply with our policies. It could mean that we cancel a product or service you have with us.

Any data collection that is optional would be made clear at the point of collection.

* * *

### Marketing

We may use your personal information to tell you about relevant products and offers. This is what we mean when we talk about ‘marketing’.

The personal information we have for you is made up of what you tell us, and data we collect when you use our services, or from third parties we work with.

We study this to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you.

We can only use your personal information to send you marketing messages if we have either your consent or a ‘legitimate interest’. That is when we have a business or commercial reason to use your information. It must not unfairly go against what is right and best for you.

You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages by contacting us at any time.

Whatever you choose, you’ll still receive statements, and other important information such as changes to your existing products and services.

We may ask you to confirm or update your choices, if you take out any new products or services with us in future. We will also ask you to do this if there are changes in the law, regulation, or the structure of our business.

If you change your mind you can update your choices at any time by contacting us.

* * *

### How long we keep your personal information

We will keep your personal information for as long as you are a customer of DotNetPages Ltd Group.

After you stop being a customer, we may keep your data for up to 10 years for one of these reasons:

  * To respond to any questions or complaints.
  * To show that we treated you fairly.
  * To maintain records according to rules that apply to us.
  * For historical statistical purposes
  * For technical reasons to better understand the use of our services

We may keep your data for longer than 10 years if we cannot delete it for legal, regulatory or technical reasons. We may also keep it for research or statistical purposes. If we do, we will make sure that your privacy is protected and only use it for those purposes.

* * *

### How to get a copy of your personal information

You can access your personal information we hold by contacting us via our [ Support Page](https://www.oddsmonkey.com/More/Support.aspx)

* * *

### Letting us know if your personal information is incorrect

You have the right to question any information we have about you that you think is wrong or incomplete. Please contact us if you want to do this.

If you do, we will take reasonable steps to check its accuracy and correct it.

* * *

### What if you want us to stop using your personal information?

You have the right to object to our use of your personal information, or to ask us to delete, remove, or stop using your personal information if there is no need for us to keep it. This is known as the ‘right to object’ and ‘right to erasure’, or the ‘right to be forgotten’.

There may be legal or other official reasons why we need to keep or use your data. But please tell us if you think that we should not be using it.

You can ask us to restrict the use of your personal information if:

  * It is not accurate.
  * It has been used unlawfully but you don’t want us to delete it.
  * It not relevant any more, but you want us to keep it for use in legal claims.
  * You have already asked us to stop using your data but you are waiting for us to tell you if we are allowed to keep on using it.

If you want to object to how we use your data, or ask us to delete it or restrict how we use it or, please contact us.

* * *

### How to withdraw your consent

You can withdraw your consent at any time. Please contact us if you want to do so.

If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. If this is so, we will tell you.

* * *

### How to complain

Please let us know if you are unhappy with how we have used your personal information. You can contact us using our [secure online contact form](https://www.oddsmonkey.com/More/Support.aspx).

You also have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office. Find out on their website how to [report a concern](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/).

* * *

### Future formats for sharing data

The Data Privacy laws will change on 25 May 2018. From that date you will have the right to get your personal information from us in a format that can be easily re-used. You can also ask us to pass on your personal information in this format to other organisations.

* * *

### Cookies

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site.

* * *

### Changes to this policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.
